The inflow of these stablecoins is an indicator that buyers are coming in because most retail
users don't actually buy or mint USDT. Bonnie, have you minted USDT before?
Nope.
How do you make sure you quickly buy but you can also quickly redeem when people want their
mind back? When you're holding a stablecoin, you are holding claim to someone, right? So when you
hold USDT, you have a $1 claim to Tether. When you hold CRVUSD, you have a $1 claim to the CRVUSD
smart contract. You have to trust that the issuer of that stablecoin is going to give you your
mind back because you have to believe that the person who you're going to give a stablecoin
to also believe that.
You talked about the inflation in Argentina. Can you just help me visualize how bad it is?
You lose context of what things are worth. Let's say you take a two month trip somewhere, you
come back and you have to think about the prices in the supermarket in US dollars. How many layers
of risk are you taking when you're buying some of these centralis stablecoins? Probably tens
of layers. You didn't want to go wrong. The sophisticated actor is going to get up very
quickly and then you're going to be holding the bag.
The value of ETH comes from its utility as if you like digital oil, like the power of
the Ethereum blockchain. So as the transactions move to layer two, I do want what the price
will be of ETH as a gas, you know, in layer one. So that might affect long term projections
of the value.
If you want success then take a look away.
If you want success, then take a look away.
Okay, hello guys.
We have Elvin from D-Day.
Hello.
Martin from Mountain Protocol.
Hey, good morning.
And we have Chris from Mr. Block.
Yay.
Howdy.
Hello, hello.
Ni hao.
Okay, we're going to talk about stablecoins today.
And I feel like recently we received a surge in stablecoins.
And the total stablecoin market cap is at $150 billion right now.
What does the influence outflow of these stablecoins tell you about the market?
I've been in the crypto since 2011.
That's when I first bought Bitcoin.
And then, you know, back in the days, there wasn't Tether.
You know, they weren't USDC.
It's Ophia, right?
People buy Bitcoin with Taiwan dollar.
People buy crypto with RMB, with USD.
When I first saw Tether, it was around 2013, 2014, 2015.
It was on the Omni layer, the Omni chain.
The total TBI was like a million, I think, when I first saw it.
There was no one using it, right?
And then, obviously, it really became huge in 2017 when Chinese government decided to ban crypto exchange.
And people have to find a way to kind of go through these loopholes.
That's where the stablecoin came out.
I want to give this little background because ever since then, it became a way to track these inflow and outflow.
Because before that, it was impossible because we wouldn't know how much money these exchange kept in the bank account, right?
We wouldn't know if they're a billion dollar, $10 billion.
There was no transparency report.
The idea didn't even exist.
USDT became one of the main stablecoins on Binance.
And Binance became one of the largest crypto exchange, surpassing Kraken, Coinbase, and everyone else.
From then, it became obvious the inflow of these stablecoins is an indicator that buyers are coming in.
Because most retail users don't actually buy or mint USDT.
Bonnie, have you minted USDT before?
Nope.
Nope, right?
So most of us, we're retails.
If they want to put in 10 mil or 100 mil or a billion, dare I say, they'll go through these stablecoin companies.
From then, it became an indicator.
So coming back to your question, I think it's still a really strong indicator.
After 2017, USDT, USDC die.
Multiple type of stablecoin design, multi-collateral design, single collateral design, the maker now, liquidity design, outgo stablecoin design.
There's multiple way to design these stablecoins.
But all in all, it will come down to USDT.
That became one of the main indicators to know that, okay, the market is getting hot again.
So I think it's still a strong indicator.
I very much agree with that.
I would say the way I look at it is stablecoins kind of thinking about the use cases, right?
So the first use case, as Chris said, is trading and trading settlement.
So you would see USDT being used to settle between exchanges and move out of BTC settlement into stablecoin settlement.
I think USDT has grown through the last bear market substantially.
And at least in my mental model, that is a different use case, which is emerging economies saving account.
A ton of people that hold 1,000 USDT, 10,000 USDT, or combines that hold 10 million USDT as a way of holding the equivalent of a US dollar bank account.
And that is a use case that I think is taking over USDT and it's explaining a lot of the growth of USDT, and especially doing the bear market.
And then you have the use case of kind of DeFi, I think mostly owned by USDC, right, on L2s and so on.
The last piece that I'm seeing recently on the stablecoin development is kind of like a move out of stablecoins back again, right?
So you see large institutions that are trading in exchanges and are supposed to keeping stablecoins in exchange
as a way to trade, they're doing a triparty arrangement using a bank account with T-bills, so they can capture the 5% yield while trading in that exchange.
A lot of the compression in stablecoin volumes has been due to that.
Now the market is heating up, there's lots of inflows, but there are those outflows.
So going back to crisis tracking what's happening, I think we're starting to lose track again, given these triparty arrangements, especially for large traders in many of these exchanges.
And a little bit of what we hope to do is to make that in this market so we can continue to keep track and return on your stablecoins and actually use the stablecoins as they're meant to be.
So all in all, I would say market is heating up, use like stablecoins coming in, retail using stablecoins for other use cases other than trading, mostly savings account.
But also you see an outflow on these triparty arrangements, which are quite substantial, or hundreds of millions of dollars or billions of dollars in some cases.
So how do stablecoin issuers make money?
Yes, I can go to that question.
If you look at USDT, they've been public about how much money they make.
They make a lot more money than Ethereum gas fees.
I think 2x the money that every user spends on Ethereum gas fees.
From a fintech perspective, it's one of the best fintechs ever built in the history, right?
Probably compared to PayPal or Stripe or something like that.
The way they make money is if you give them a dollar, they put a dollar to work, hopefully it would be a 5%.
We don't know exactly what the tether is.
They say they're investing into a biotech company.
That money is getting invested and you as the holder of USDT or USDC, you're earning 0% from that value.
The equivalent to a USDT or USDC would be like holding stake fee.
But Lite are charging 100% of the yield.
So they pass you zero.
When you look at value that way, it's kind of insane.
But that's the amount of money they make.
And Lite is taking is currently paying 3%.
Short-term treasuries are paying 5%.
So it's almost double the revenue Ethereum staking and they get to keep 100%.
That is the biggest dollars every year that the whole crypto ecosystem is getting sucked out of the crypto ecosystem for these insurers.
And essentially generating a lot of drag in the ecosystem.
Okay, Chris, do you have anything to add?
I think stablecoin issuer has a really strong edge here.
And it's rightfully there.
It has all these use cases everywhere in crypto.
Obviously talking about USDT.
They don't really have to give any of those yields to USDT holder.
Tether is one of the biggest T-bill buyer.
They don't really share any of those yields to USDT holder.
And USDT holder would actually have to pay a minting fee and a redemption fee.
Right?
So essentially they have, like Martha said, one of the best fintech design ever.
And all they really have to do is make sure that one is they don't get taken down.
And I think that's one of the reasons they're buying so much T-bill.
And it's trying to get USDT accepted everywhere.
Right?
So everyone is on this boat.
If it gets taken down, then you have more of hundreds of millions of people that host USDT.
And all its competitors are trying really hard.
So I think there's always going to be pros and cons when it comes to stablecoin.
I think, you know, Tether has a very unique position, but that doesn't mean that other
stablecoin protocol will not have its time.
We like to see, you know, more and more choices for these stablecoin protocols and a stablecoin
company.
And, you know, I like to say that there are different types of stablecoins out there.
And, you know, on Curve, there's CRB USDT, and their use cases are very, very different.
When it comes to creating a stablecoin, it's not only about these pure yields.
It's also about how do you find these target audience and create a product that's catered to them
and keep growing.
So it's Athena, right, Athena recently created a very interesting use cases that previously
people weren't really looking at it.
So USDT now has around 1.3 billion shows that people that are able to take high risks.
These people are similar to Luna, right?
Luna USDT user.
I'm not saying Athena is kind of like Luna, but I'm saying that it also has this high yields
to attract people.
And that's like opposite from Tether, where Tether don't give you any yields and charge a
lot of money because everyone everywhere can use it.
So people use Tether.
But then on the other spectrum, you have protocol that wants to track these 1% of users that want
high yields.
If you have a check, it has 70% of the market cap.
If there are other stablecoin issuers that get more attractive, like yield, why is USDT
still dominating?
It's like Visa and MasterCard.
If you're trying to create a new credit card network, it is very, very hard because each
customer you go talk to, they want their merchants to accept it.
So they want to use that last thing and get it accepted.
And each merchant you talk to wants consumers that can actually pay for that card.
So in the end, you're kind of like in a chicken and an egg problem where the network
effect of acceptability or people accepting USDT as an equivalent of $1 is very, very deep
for USDT.
USDC has not been able to break that at the point where USDT is, right?
Like I'm from Argentina.
When I go there and try to buy Argentinian pesos with crypto, the people who exchange will only
take USDT on track.
That's the only thing that they accept in crypto.
So that is the biggest reason is acceptability.
People like education of this mass market is not that easy.
And the acceptability that USDT gets gives it a very strong guarantee around the $1 because
there's always someone willing to take the USDT around $1.
So the purpose of the asset being more transactional and the acceptability that asset has gives
it a very strong moat when we are trying to get in or our team is trying to get in or
we're trying to get into that space.
It's astounding to me that the traditional stablecoins like USDT and USDC, we don't see,
they take so much of the yield.
When we saw Martin Protocol Act, there's a great replication that you could have a unit of
account that's tied to the US dollar, but also generating yield as it sits there.
In this case, he gates.
So my suspicion is that the era of USDT dominance is not going away anytime soon, but it's slowly
being eroded by all these new models eventually.
We are going to talk about all the different types of stablecoins because when I talk to
people like my uncle or my auntie, a lot of people outside of crypto, they do not understand
the concept of stablecoin.
They think these issuers are printing money out of thin air.
We do have a lot of different types of stablecoins.
And can you give us examples of the specific type of stablecoin and explain to us the process
of making each type of stablecoin?
What has to happen before you create, for example, one USDT or like one USDM?
Let's start with Martin.
Do you want to talk about fiat stablecoins?
Yeah, I would say fiat-back stablecoins are stablecoins backed with cash equivalents.
When you give us a dollar, give USDT or USDC a dollar, what happens is we will go, we will
turn around, give that dollar to a custodian and they will buy one dollar worth of very
short term US treasuries or a repo or something, which in accounting is called cash equivalents.
That way that money is essentially let out to the US government.
The US government will pay you 5% interest for doing that transaction.
And that is held as Calaro.
The quality or the legal claim in that Calaro is a big question, right?
Like how safe is that from the issue of going down?
I think there's different, there's a different palette of colors in how safe that is, but
everyone essentially has a resource held in T-bos.
And then on the other side, there is a minting of that new USDT, USDM that is given to the
primary buyer.
In this case, usually institutional buyers.
So for one dollar that comes in, it turns into a T-bill and that turns into an ERC-coining
that gets out.
So essentially it's a T-bill on the back and then ERC-coining in the front.
That is the definition of fiat-back stablecoin.
And the challenge of running these models is how do you make sure you quickly buy, but
you can also quickly redeem when people want their buy back.
And it's all about building a very strong financial IPP to that operation.
Chris, do you want to talk about crypto-backed stablecoins?
We talked a lot about the fiat ones and then how it generates from T-bill.
You know, crypto is in a very different way where mostly it's over-collateralized.
And it all started with a single collateral designed by MakerDAO where it used ETH as collateral.
And, you know, before we moved from proof of work to proof of stake, voting ETH has zero
yields.
So it wasn't this concept or it wasn't possible to have collateral to earn yields.
Not like how Tether convinced USDT or USDN for Mountain to earn from T-bill.
From now, with LRT protocol and LSD, it is now possible for multi-collateral back or single
collateral back LSD stablecoin that generates 4% to 5% yield similar to T-bill in an ETH format.
So a good example of this protocol is Prisma, which uses LRT protocol.
So essentially on top of the 4% or 5% yields that generated from using your ETH as collateral,
you will also earn down the line protocols such as eigenlayer and Puffer Finance or ETH.
So that's the beauty about these crypto backed stablecoin is that it gives you access to DeFi.
When you come into DeFi, there is smart contract risks, all type of counterparty risk, you know,
and you can lose your private key, for example.
In return, you have high yields from these protocols.
In the current market, there's three main stablecoin protocols.
And that is the MakerDAO design, which you'll need liquidator to come in and liquidate.
While all of them have it, MakerDAO specifically, you need liquidator to come in.
If ETH price goes down, then use the stability pool to go and buy these trope that has a lower
collateral ratio.
And then there is Curve and the Abbey model.
The Curve design is kind of learning from the previous two design and have what we call
soft liquidation.
So that instead of having this really harsh liquidation when it comes to these Black Swan
events, we have this more of a soft lending design.
When we talk about crypto backed stablecoin, right?
Crypto backed, everything's on chain.
So you could have liquidator that will just jump in and try to profit from these positions.
In Curve design, if your collateral price goes down, you don't instantly get liquidated
because the price might jump back up.
It doesn't get fully liquidated.
You still have a chance to kind of slowly get packed back.
So the idea is that let's say you have a million dollar worth of ETH as collateral and
the protocol means, let's say a hundred K.
That means you are a thousand percent collateral ratio.
And let's say all of a sudden, you know, ETH for some reason went down to like, I don't
know, a hundred dollars or something.
And then theoretically the whole position could be liquidated.
So having a soft liquidation essentially needed time to pack back.
And most of the time, a packer can use this thing called flash long.
So the whole thing has to happen in one block.
Anything outside of one block is not possible or not profitable.
Soft liquidation also help us protect from these potential exploiters that could exploit
the protocol.
And it also makes sure that the stable coin venture don't lose that much money.
And just like what Martin said before, right?
USDT has this mold.
And then even with Perf, where we think we have a very innovative design of stable coin,
it still comes down to how many people actually do CRB USD and who wants it and how much
yield can we really get out.
And I can tell you having these over collateralized stable coins.
So imagine you go to a bank and you want to borrow a hundred dollars.
You give the bank $300 deposit and you borrow a hundred dollars.
It makes much sense.
LRT, I think it's possible.
That's why we think these LRT backed stable coin has a lot of chances and then Kerr stable
coin enhance that in a way that not only you have these LRT yields, but on top of that,
you can use it in the Kerr ecosystem.
That's great.
Thank you so much, Chris.
Let's talk about Elgo, Elgo stable coin.
I think the classic example that everyone would know is Terra Luna.
It crashed, but before that, everyone thought it was the best thing since sliced bread because
you could get high yields, right?
So essentially what an algorithmic stable coin does is that through smart contracts and some kind of algorithm,
it ties the value of the stable coin to the US dollar.
The cool thing is that there's no centralized force doing this, which is also a potential
for disaster.
In the case of Terra Luna, the UST was packed for the dollar.
Anytime that the UST went below the value of the dollar, you could swap it for $1 worth of
Luna and then the price was start to go back up as people bought UST and vice versa.
So this mechanism is very clever in maintaining the pack of UST to a dollar.
However, the problem comes when obviously there's a run and people lose confidence in the
lunar ecosystem, the Terra ecosystem.
And that's exactly what happened.
There was a death spiral, as we all know, and Luna UST went to zero.
So this is obviously in hindsight a flawed design, but the beauty of it was that it was
so captivating and it just gave high yields and it was automatic.
At the time, I seriously thought that Luna could succeed because it had an ecosystem back
it up.
This is a classic example of the other thing.
Very dangerous, but very sexy.
I would say to sum up, I think when you're holding a stable coin, you are holding claim
to someone, right?
So when you hold UST, you have a $1 claim to Tether.
When you hold CRD UST, you have a $1 claim to the CRD UST smart contract.
You have to trust that the issuer with that stable coin is going to give you your money back
because you have to believe that the person who you're going to give that stable coin
to also believes that.
You drink directly from the source.
So US dollars issued by the US government.
US tables are the US government debt essentially.
So you're directly at the source.
And then you can get into more creative ways of actually building this like a very good
claim.
The issue, the trade off here is the creativity brings a lot of value, right?
So the yield related to crypto max stable coins is definitely today higher than the yield
created by the US government.
But there is a trade off with how easy it is to explain to the person you're going to give
that dollar to, but they're going to go and be able to actually claim it back.
And the more complex the design, I think it gets interesting from a study perspective,
but it gets a lot harder to explain the person you're going to give that dollar to afterwards
why they should trust that that claim is going to be.
Let's talk about mounted protocol USDM then.
USDM is a new stable coin backed by UST bills.
What is the story behind creating USDM?
My background, I've been working in traditional banks for almost 10 years, very familiar with
like deposit and lending institutions.
I've been in crypto.
I'm from Argentina.
So very serious situation.
Like we have a lot of inflation.
I got started buying Bitcoin.
That was the first thing I could buy essentially from inflation and being in the crypto space ever
I was like, you know, I'm going to put my money in the US T bills.
I'm surprised at the gap.
At the time the US T bills were paying 1.7%.
And now it was zero point something.
So I was essentially looking at it and just putting money in T bills myself.
I was like, it's ridiculous that then I clicked.
It's ridiculous that circle is making all this money.
Teller is making all this money.
And then people are putting it taking smart contract risk, putting their ETH in a smart contract.
And the circle is doing nothing and they're getting 1.7%.
There has to be, someone has to have solved this problem.
I also had my mom asking me, okay, what should I do with my money?
Because I also my.
And also my.
come down, but we have to create a stablecoin that is fair for the user in that it's not
extracting all the value, it's actually paying most of the value to the holder in the form of rewards.
So that was the insight for USDM. Then on the implementation side, this happened in 2022.
On the implementation side, we were very much around how do we build this to be future-proof,
right? Like we know this is not going to be a DGEN product. DGENs, they're going to go for
riskier products further in the riskier. This is for people who want to be conservative. How do we
make sure we build Mountain Protocol with the best guarantees that you have? So we decided to go
go regulated. So we are one of the only regulated stablecoin issuers and the only geo-baring stable
coin issuer. What that means when you say regulated is you're trusting us, but you're also trusting a
regulator that is pulling their stamp that we're doing things properly from audits, from how we
manage your processes and everything else. And then the quality of your asset is a lot better.
And especially for institutionals, they really like USDM and how it's built and it gives them a lot
more comfort. It took almost 18 months to get all of that there. And we launched our Q4 last year
and they're currently sitting at around 150 million EVL, just to PayPal, which is like $1 million
ahead of us. So probably we'll pass them soon. Wow. Congratulations. You talked about the
inflation in Argentina. Can you just help me visualize how bad it is? Several things. People
that have not lived in high inflation environments have a very hard time imagining what it looks like.
So first thing, since 2011, which was my first salary, which went to Bitcoin, I have never seen
inflation in Argentina below 40% per year. That has been the minimum. Last year, the inflation was,
there were some months of 300% annual inflation. So anything from 40 to 300 was kind of what we've seen
in the last kind of decade. What does that inflation mean? You lose context of what things are worth.
Let's say you take a two month trip somewhere, you come back and you have to think about the prices
in the supermarket in US dollars, because if you think they don't make any sense when you think
about them. Because in two months, you might have had 20% inflation. So is this cheap or not? It's
hard to get a sense. Many things change. So when a society starts to get used to that inflation,
people that wouldn't traditionally be in crypto start being on crypto. My grandma, she buys USD now.
She used to buy USDT. So she gets her retirement income in the first five days of the month,
and she buys dollars and then keeps those dollars until she needs to sell to pay her credit card. She's 89 and
she doesn't make that much money. But everyone is the CFO in the country. If you have not gone to
Argentina, I think it's a really nice place to go and actually see economics push to their limit
and what free markets do to actually solve these things. But the biggest thing people are searching
is W, and that's why stablecoins are so popular in a place like Argentina, because even though the US
dollar fund is on inflation, 5%, 7% or 8% we had last year is nothing compared to 200. So people
mentalize 8% as between zero in terms of inflation. It's really hard for me to imagine. I actually went to
Argentina pre-COVID and it was like the most beautiful place. We were just walking dogs. Everyone's
like living their life. It's very hard to imagine all that. And the example you gave was pretty,
pretty amazing. How you go on a trip and come back. Okay. If you were to create one USDM, what has to
happen before that? Or what does the process look like? Now that we have the license and all the
financial infrastructure, creating USDM is quite simple. You can send us a US dollar, like fiat,
like a wire transfer or a swift transfer, or you can send us a USDC and we'll credit your account with one
dollar and then you can withdraw one USDM. What's going to happen in the background is once we receive the asset,
we're going to market as a dollar in the USDM reserve database. That is going to get invested,
right? Sent to an investment manager. We recently announced we're working with BlackRock's recent
fund. So that was going to be essentially managed by them. And then on the asset side, we're going
to mint a new USDM. So that means process, we usually have some USDM that we hold on balance sheet,
but if you're going to be doing a larger purchase, we're going to mint and we're going to send that to
you. So it's a very straightforward process in which money comes in, you have to send out for
investment and then no minting happens and that gets sent back to you, right? And again, our job is to
make sure that those checks and balances always work so that the USDM is always back. And when
you mint or begin, those two accounts essentially check out. Where can we find USDM and what are the
best ways to use it, to utilize it? Well, the best place to find USDM right now is DGATE. So you
reach any asset into DGATE and you get a centralized trading experience that is actually decentralized,
so you own full custody. You can use USDM for trading. I think the biggest use space today for USDM in
DGATE is you just use the, for example, ETH-USDM pair, which allows you to trade when you're in ETH,
but when you're in dollars, right on the other side of that trade, you're earning the reward rate of
USDM, which is currently at 5%. So essentially you kind of get the best of both worlds. You are
having your trading activity, but at the same time, sometimes you are long and you're in ETH and you
earn all the abs and downs of ETH, but sometimes you're short and you're earned on the USD side,
you're earning that 5%. We don't have anything about that risk. And then at the end of the day or month,
you just go and claim your reward in the US quite simple. That is amazing. Alvin, why did DGATE
decide to enter USDM? First of all, I think that as you can all see, Martin is, he knows the stuff super well.
He's, whenever I see Martin on videos, he's always to the point, Chris, his logic and warm. So I think
that the team in general is a top-notch team. I think that if you look at the background of the team,
and not just the USDM team, but the team of investors like Nick Carter from Castle Island Ventures,
I think it's Coinbase and a few others. So in my perspective, it's an easy decision. So one crucial
point is that USDM is a quote token, which means that it can be used as a unit account, like ETH versus
USDM or WBTC versus USDM or any other token versus USDM. So I think that integration is because we saw how
how committed and how clear thinking and long-term thinking the team was. One important
philosophical point is that $1 has to be $1. So USDM, because of rebases, the unit of account is $1,
the 5% yield is given back to you as a rebasing. So maybe in the year, you have 100 USDM, you get
5 USDM more as a rebase. So philosophically, people over time will tend to see something like USDM as a
unit of account, as $1. And that helps them to make decisions. I think that it has been helpful to the
DGATE ecosystem to have USDM in it. On the unit of account, I think if you're going to have a stablecoin,
you have to be able to pay for coffee without pulling up your calculator and CoinGecko to find
actual prices. So if I'm going to be paying for coffee with SDI or with BTC or with whatever,
right? Like whatever non-stablecoin, you have to do so many steps that in the end, that friction will
make it such that you're not going to do it. Okay, great. We talk about all the great stuff
about stablecoins, but we want to touch on the risk. Earlier on, you talked about Luna UST, right?
I want to ask you if you have seen any other type of algo stablecoin that are alive and doing okay,
doing well, what are they doing differently than UST? Oh, we kind of have Athena, which, you know,
one might argue that it's not an algo stable or it is an algo stable. It relies on a mix of collateral
and some sort of a mechanic, these long, short trading strategy to maintain PEG is an algo stable.
And I think right now, the hype is around Athena, you know, having supporter from Deribit, BitMEX,
Arthur Hayes, Binance, you name it. Everyone is kind of like in their realm and kind of supporting that.
So I think that's also an important ingredient for successful algo stablecoin. There's the spiral.
There is a potential where the asset they use as collateral to DPAC or go below or go undervalued
due to any sort of black swan event. In this case, it's hard to do it. But I think Athena might be
able to do it just because they have learned from all these previous cases and kind of build these
prevention mechanism that allows it to not go into your crazy death spiral. USD is kind of an algo stable
as well, right? USD is probably under-collateralized, but it has a bunch of use cases, a bunch of venues,
and everyone believe it. And they have the biggest, dopest army in the world. So everyone's afraid
of it. So, you know, even though it's under-collateralized, it's still PEG. I think everyone
is not wrong trying to recreate something like that in crypto. And whoever that can actually do it,
might be as successful as Bitfinex, you know, because essentially, you will not only be able to
print money out from thin air, but you will also be able to convince a bunch of people to use it.
Then that is one of the greatest creation, if possible. How did Luna work? Is you use Luna as
collateral and you mint USD? And if USD goes below PEG, then you mint more Luna and then it goes in.
But then as panic heads in, people start selling USD, then you mint more Luna. I think it is possible
to save it if they just decide not to mint any Luna and just be like, let it be packed for a while.
If we think about it, right? USDC was D-packed for two days during the Second Valley Bank crisis. And
actually it was D-packed for a week, if we think about it. And if you give it enough time and for
people to calm down, then there are ways to save it. It's the same thing why, you know, the Fed raised
interest rate, right? It's kind of to ensure fear, right? To tell people like, you should stop
spending money or you should start spending money. It's not as effective retail, but it is incredibly
effective when you want to tell a story to be like, yo, the inflation is high right now, or we are in
a quantitative easing or we're strengthening, right? So it's about that message. So I think a lot of
people that are designing stablecoin have to remember how important it is to communicate to
the retail and tell them to be like, yo, I know ship has hit the fence, but you guys got to calm down
and then not to sell, right? And then try to figure stuff out. And I think at that time, Luna had a chance to
kind of communicate, but at the same time, they keep printing money. If they decide to stop printing Luna,
wait out of bed for 10 days, they might have a chance. We can play this chat GPT and see if
the scenario works out. Yeah. Yeah. Because practically, yeah, it sounds right, but could
they actually do it? Yeah. I think DoPuan or their team has a key, right? They can
sign the multi-state to stop printing. Yeah, definitely. But any of these
decentralized stablecoins are not as decentralized as claimed. The way I look at risk as stablecoins
is very much going back into how banks manage risk. So when you have a stablecoin, you usually have
$1 of backing for $1 of liability. Usually there's some form of impairment on the collateral,
right? So instead of having $1 to $1, you have $0.98 to $1. You have $0.02 that are not going to be
recoverable, at least for the short term. And what you end up having is the smart people that have
this dollar, they're going to claim it back to capture the $0.98 to make sure that they're not
left with the loss. And that's what generates the bank run. And then the last person to go in,
usually retail, will get zero. And in Luna, we saw that some of the sophisticated actors
exited and made a ton of money with Luna, and then retail ended up holding it back. I think the
issue that we see with many of the stablecoins getting created is they assume everything is going to go
well. And the level of counterparty risk that gets layered on top of layers of counterparty risk on
the collateral side, you need one thing to go wrong for the whole stablecoin to create a background.
So that is the thing. I'm a big skeptic on having my grandma buy any kind of like crypto back stable
coins or algorithmic stable coins, because I believe my grandma, she's going to be holding the back,
right? Like she's not sophisticated. I think that applies to many people in retail. How many layers
of risk are you taking when you're buying some of these essentially stablecoins? Probably tens of layers.
You didn't want to go wrong. The sophisticated actor is going to get up very quickly. And then you're
going to be holding the back. I think that's the risk that you should be looking when you're looking
to buy a stablecoin or actually any type of asset. I think stablecoins, particularly given the leverage,
is am I going to be the fast capital leading or am I going to be the slow capital holding the back?
And if you're in the slow capital holding the back, you need to make sure that it's never going to
explode. And the simpler the model, the less likely it is to actually explode. When I think about
the risks for fiat-back stablecoins, it's very, fairly simple. You already have tables. Those tables,
could they be impaired? Potentially yes, if the US government decides to default. Unlikely because they can always
print more. So they would most likely print more than default, but potentially. But outside of that,
even if the smart contract gets hacked, for example, or if there's some sort of impairment on the asset
side, the T-bos still exists. You can always go back, sell them and give people their money back. So I think
fiat-back stablecoins in general, if you trust the management and if you trust that their processes are
sound, it is a fairly safe model. Once you start adding risk, so for example, a pool of stablecoins,
and you're going to say, I'm going to buy four or five different stablecoins to create another stablecoin on
the other side, you are taking the risk of the worst of those stablecoins. Because if one collapses, let's say you have
five, 20% each, one collapses. Now you have 80 cents per dollar. People are going to leave. So very
quickly, you're going to have 20 cents or 40 cents in assets. So you lost 50%. In my opinion, if you're
a sophisticated actor, you should look at these risks and monitor them and make sure you live quickly.
If you're not a sophisticated actor, try not to put money you're not willing to lose into these types
of strategies because the level of risks are multiple and only one of those is going to create
a loss. And if you're slow, you're going to eat all of the loss yourself. I love that because you
know how people usually compare all this stablecoin that which is better, but I think you broke it down really
well. Just look at the risk and yeah, I love that. Thank you. My perspective as a buyer standard of
like these evolving dynamics is I'm reminded of the quote from Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet where
the fire says, these violent delights have violent ends. So what makes a stablecoin attractive sometimes
is the yield for Terra. And that's also part of the downfall sometimes because these yields,
I don't see how they're sustainable sometimes. And I think we're seeing a bit of that dynamic happening
again this bull run. However, how do you make a stablecoin popular? I think that one way is to have great
yield, that's for sure. The other way is great marketing. And on the other end of the spectrum is
trust and operations. So I think that doing the right thing to get the distribution of this
important, I hate to say this, but Tron has done a good job with USCP on Tron.
If you're a company, the salaries for your employees for next month, you're probably not going to put
them on something experimental. If you have $100 and you just want to try something and potentially
farm an airdrop or something like that, you might go further on the risker. As always, you have to
think about what type of investment that you're doing, whether it's about cash preservation or
capital preservation or whether it's I'm going to take risk on this because I think I can get a big
reward. The word stablecoin usually tries to confuse the latter, the high yield, and try to mimic the risk of the former.
So it's like, why would you hold X, very high yield, very stablecoin and not hold USDT or USDC if it was the same risk?
And I think that the key thing for people buying these assets is basically they're not the same
math. And then think about separating if there's a risk, but there's a risk reward difference.
There's another big topic in stablecoin, which is regulation. We all saw how the US government
ordered Pixos to stop issuing BUSD last year in 2023. Why only BUSD? Do you see that's happening to other
stablecoins? I think the BUSD one, there's a lot of things that we need to clarify, lots of things that
happen behind the curtains that many of us don't know. I think what we do know was that Circle kind
of tipped the regulators in that Binance was bridging BUSD into their chain and that the collateral
held on Ethereum was not backing one-to-one the Binance chain assets. The other thing that the NGFS
was not comfortable is they had not allowed issuance of BUSD on that chain. And that was the argument to
actually shut that down. But I think it was a warning when you deal with certain types of regulators,
you need to follow their regulations. But then the bridging, I think, was potentially a great area
actually following that regulation. It is not easy to work with regulators. It's like getting married.
Right? So the decisions that you usually took as a single startup, you're not taking as a couple.
You have the startup and you have the regulators and you're not always agree. And it's always the
decisions are not as fast and there's a lot of traders. But on the flip side of that, as buying
an asset that is regulated, you get the advantages of knowing that two different people with different
interests have looked at this and have said that whatever they're doing is okay. That stablecoins
will continue to be regulated when, I'm going to use my grandma again, but when my grandma holds a stablecoin,
she thinks she has a claim to a dollar that very much looks like a bank deposit. Right? So she thinks she has
something very similar to a bank of America deposit or her local bank deposit. She doesn't think she
owns a portfolio of a long, short trade collateralized with a multi-asset. She doesn't think she owns that
like a hedge fund position. But I think they're going to continue to be regulated as closer to banks or
as payment companies. And as we march forward with that regulation, I think many other things will
have to be stopped called stablecoins. I don't know if they're going to use a stablecoin term or they're
going to change it, but I think there's going to be a bifurcation into potentially fiat-back stablecoins
being regulated and then all the other assets potentially having to change things.
We look at the historical data Bitcoin pre and post having, the price usually drop, right? And we wait
for a few months, the price goes up again. Chris, why does this happen?
I don't know, actually. I mean, I've seen it happening for so many times. And I think the idea
is the original idea, at least back in 2012, I think was the miners want to hedge a little bit,
right? Because their rewards are getting half. If you are making X amount of money per day,
and you know that tomorrow, everything you make will be a quarter of that or half of that. So your idea would be
to hedge it, right? Because you have electricity costs, you have rents, you have to pay for your
Bitcoin farm, right? So you will sell your Bitcoin reward and then monitor a bit. And if the price
goes back up, great. But if the price doesn't go back up, you still have the money that you sold
free happening. So you have enough treasury to maintain your Bitcoin farm and to sustain until
if the price go up, right? So that's the original idea of why Bitcoin price always drop before happening.
I think the other part that I'm very bullish on is the simple math of what's happening with the
BTC. For every Bitcoin miners produce, there's 10 Bitcoin getting purchased by institutional buyers
of ETFs, right? So the mining inflation, if you will, is getting eaten up by this kind of new demand.
Now that mining inflation is going to go from one Bitcoin to half a Bitcoin for this,
like purchase amount of 10. Many of these institutions are getting started. So to me,
like the part that I'm trying to figure out is where there's a price at which all of this money
getting in will clear with a new supply of BTC, which is essentially miners, but people will need to sell.
I think we still haven't found that either. I think there's more inflows coming from more
institutions starting on the BTC ETF that have not turned it on and the current institutions
continuing to build in that portfolio allocation of Bitcoin. The last thing I'm excited about,
I know it's going to happen that the ETF ever gets approved. And if it does this year,
I think you're going to see the dynamic of the BTC ETF, but in PowerDrive, right? Like most of the
people who run nodes keep their ETH. So it's going to be a scramble to find buyers of ETH. And I think
that can create a lot of interest and a lot of appreciation on this side. You might be
doing versus securing an ETH note, right? So proof of work versus proof of stake. In proof of work,
you have to do a lot of actual work. So you have to buy very expensive machines and you have to pay
for a lot of electricity. So if you look at like this miners, it's a very competitive game. You
actually don't make a lot of profit and because they need to eat, right? So it's pay this electricity
bills and pay this hardware. They need to sell most of it. When you're running a ETH note, you cannot
run it on your Raspberry Pi, right? It's a pretty approach. Like a retail laptop, you can run an ETH note.
It doesn't consume a lot. And therefore, most of what you earn, you can keep, you don't have to be spending a lot.
So that means if you're running a note, but most likely you're a very bull ETH person to start with.
Plus you're not forced to sell because you don't have to pay for any expenses.
I don't think many of those are going to be selling.
Alvin, what do you think is going to happen this long run?
The traditional idea of a four-year cycle is an interesting dynamic between Bitcoin and ETH,
right? So Bitcoin is known as, at least to us, as the digital gold, is like the store value.
Whereas ETH is fundamentally not seen as a store value or accepted as a store value. So the value of
ETH comes from its utility as, if you like, a digital oil that powers the Ethereum blockchain. So as the
transactions move to layer two, I do wonder what the price will be of ETH as a gas in layer one. So that
might affect long-term projections of the value because the model is one of valuing it via the utility of
the ETH rather than a digital gold. So on the one hand, I'm bullish with the Ethereum ETF,
hopefully upcoming. But on the other hand, it's fundamentally a different product from Bitcoin
in my mind. To the point of bull run, it's all macro, right? Crypto is an amplifier of the macro
environment. So my personal opinion, not financial advice system, macro environment is bullish right
now. It will be until the end of the year, more or less, but true this nobody knows. So I'm bullish on
this year.
I love that. Yeah. With the Ethereum ETF though, isn't it hard to explain to, let's say your
grandma, what ETH is? It's easier to explain what digital gold is. Bitcoin doesn't have, which is
native yield, right? So it is easier to sell the product where you say, you don't need to believe
that ETH price is going to go up as long as you have some native yield on your ETH. And I think for
trans-fight people, specifically for institutions, it's very easy to understand that type of product
because you don't need to have someone else come and buy from you at a higher price. You're just
accruing more value on a daily basis despite pricing flat. Elvin, what are some trends that you're paying attention to this world
What's super interesting is the rise of RWAs and USDM, for example, as like the EO-Baring stablecoin. So it's on one side of the spectrum and the other side obviously is mean points. Mean coins is like, if stable coins, back by fiat, make a lot of sense, mean coins are on the other end of the spectrum, they make absolutely no sense. Except like as an expression of animal spirits, right? People just want to gamble on something. Isn't that crazy that we have two ends of the spectrum in the same crypto space? Dex is like DGate, which is an audible dex that you can easily trade, spot and do a lot of yield, yield strategies like grid strategy. Other dexes are interesting, like ETH and UNISO. So yeah, I think the dex is going to get increasingly important.
Chris, what are some trends and narratives that you're paying attention to?
Chris
!
off的交易手续费减免
用下面的连结注册呢
你的交易成本就更低了
也欢迎告诉我你接下来想要看什么
我们在币圈继续努力
下一次见 拜拜